GABRIEL'S CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name : GABRIEL LEE KIN HENG

Gender : Male
Health : Excellent
Marital Status : Single
Race : Chinese
Religion : Buddhism

Nationality : Malaysian (Singapore PR)



CAREER OBJECTIVE

To use my knowledge and skills applied towards achieving the corporate goals and to be a valuable asset to the organization. To secure a challenging position in a reputable organization to expand my knowledge about new and emerging trends in the IT sector.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

I have about 8 years' work experience in IT sector. Currently I am Application Consultant at CPF Board. I currently involved in the Healthcare project, my main responsibilities are conducting requirement gathering, reviewing and analyzing the system design and also doing the development using JAVA, NodeJS and related web programming.

I used to be a System Analyst at StarHub Ltd, my main responsibilities were maintaining StarHub's Enterprise Web Application and ChatBot system, conducting requirement gathering, analyzing existing system and user's requirement, project schedule planning, system design, system implementation and UAT testing when there is any new requirement or enhancement project.

I used to be a Web Application Developer at NCS Pte Ltd but most of the time I was allocated at IRAS to handled and developed the new project initialed by IRAS. The primary technical skills

required for IRAS project are HTML, JavaScript, CSS, C#, ASP.Net, SQL Server, DB2 database etc.

I have successfully completed more than 5 times complete SDLC (included planning, analysis, design, development, implementation and testing) and obtained Agile Scrum Master cert (PSM 1) in 2016.

EXPERIENCE

June 2019 – Current

Central Provident Fund Board

Application Consultant

- Manage outsourced vendors to implement and maintain IT applications in cloud environment
- Analyse requirements and perform high level feasibility study for IT solution
- Review impact analysis, design of IT solution and cost estimation proposed by outsourced vendor
- Perform quality checks on IT solution
- Monitor and provide updates for project development phases and deliverables
- Design and develop the software testing automation script using Tricentic Tosca
- Provide support to users of the IT application systems
- Work with Cloud service provider, application vendors and other agency to ensure systems delivered are resilient and secured

Reason of leaving:

• Looking for permanent role and better professional growth

Nov 2016 – May 2019

StarHub Ltd

System Analysts

- Manage customer-facing application for enterprise business and consumer markets.
- Defined enterprise self-care application roadmap based on operational needs, sales requirement, customers' feedback and market trends.
- Analyze consumer and business trends based on statistics obtained from numerous operational systems and feedback channels.
- Identify automation opportunities in existing processes to streamline operations, increase productivity and enhance customer experience.
- Drive successful product adoption.
- Coordinate product development of enterprise self-care system.
- Vendor engagement for development and testing.
- Design system and define the workflow according to internal and external users' need.

Projects involved:

- 1. StarHub's My Business Account (Page <u>URL</u>) This is a customer self-help portal that helping business/corporate customer to manage their account related service. In this project, my role is to defines the application problem by conferring with internal and external users. Designing the application UI, improving and analyzing the system work flow and processes. Provide reference by writing documentation and validates the result by testing the programs.
- 2. StarHub's ChatBot (Link to the application) This is a virtual assistant that simulates human conversation or chat via artificial intelligence (A.I.). The ChatBot is able to handle customer's enquiry such as Billing, Account information, Promotion, Mobile and Broadband service enquiry. My role in this project is to define the business uses case, design the system workflow, conducting the data training for machine learning and artificial intelligence, system integration and system testing. Besides, I have to engage with StarHub's customer service agent to understanding their needs and the problem they are facing so that we are able to improve the ChatBot ability.

Reason of leaving:

- I would like to look for more responsibility and grow in career, wish to get more emerge knowledge relevant to technology.
- Due to job scope changed after re-organization.

NCS Pte Ltd

Application Consultant

Projects involved:

- 1. **HRConnects (Web Application) for Ministry of Foreign Affairs Singapore** My primary role in this project is to handle and develop the contract renewal and Employee re-deployment module.
 - **Skills Used:** C#.net, ASP.net, SSRS Report tool, Microsoft SQL Server, WCF, Entity Framework, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML and CSS.
- 2. **IRAS AIS Online for Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore** To implement and develop a system that to help IRAS retrieve the employee data from CPF. Besides, I have to design and develop the IRAS E-Service web page that it is AIS Employment Income deployed on 29 December 2014
 - **Skills Used:** C#.net, DB2 database, Microsoft SQL Server, WCF, NUnit, AQT, Microsoft Visio, IBM DataStage (ETL tools), IBM Cognos Report Tool, Entity Framework, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML and CSS.
- 3. **IRAS MyInfo for Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore** Second Project for IRAS Singapore. This project is to implement web service that to help IRAS to retrieve the Taxpayer data from IDA MyInfo portal. This is the first project in IRAS to implement a web service to retrieve Taxpayer information from others government agency. Besides that, I have to setup and deploy the IBM DataPower SOA Appliance, it is to control and manage the web service traffic between IRAS and others government agency. The target deployment of this project is Jan 2016.
 - **Skills Used:** C#.net, DB2 database, Microsoft SQL Server, WCF, Entity Framework, NUnit, AQT, Microsoft Visio, IBM DataStage (ETL tools), IBM Cognos Report Tool, IBM DataPower (SOA Appliance), SOAP Web Service, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML and CSS/CSS3, Bootstrap, PowerShell Script.
- 4. **IRAS Electronic Data Exchange Gateway (EDX)** Application maintenance and support for Electronic Data Exchange (EDX) gateway system for EASY authentication for subscribing agencies.
 - **Skills Used**: Java, JSP, iPlanet, Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) and Transport Layer Security (TLS), Microsoft SQL Server, SOAP Web Service, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML and CSS.

- 5. **IRAS Case Management System (CMS)** To develop a new Case Management System, an investigative workbench for management and tracking of Taxpayer's Case records. Responsible for development of IRIN integration function in .Net and IBM DataStage (ETL tools) with Case Management System.
 - **Skills Used**: C#.Net, IBM DataStage (ETL tools), NUnit, DB2 database, Microsoft SQL Server, WCF, Entity Framework, NUnit, AQT.
- 6. **IRAS myTax Portal Web Revamps Release 3** Revamps existing IRAS' eService website (myTax Portal) to Responsive Web Design. My primary role in this project is to analyzing the system work flow, and developing the system GUI based on users' requirement.
 - **Skills Used**: C#.net, HTML, CSS3, JavaScript and JQuery, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Ajax, DB2 database, Microsoft SQL Server, WCF, Entity Framework, AQT.

Reason of leaving:

• Limited career growth and advancement

Mar 2013 - Feb 2014

Blue Ocean Data Solution SDN. BHN.

Software Engineer

- Analysis and provide pointers to those needing problem resolutions.
- Perform system design, implementation, enhancement, maintenance and support.
- Designing coding and debugging application in various software languages according SDLC.
- To evaluate the existing system or application to identify areas for improvements.
- To handle software release, installation and upgrading process.
- Develop and update operation procedure and associated SDLC documentations.
- Provide on-site technical support and system trouble shooting.
- Responsible for additional tasks as assigned by management from time to time.
- Maintaining and managing Database system.
- Responsible for meeting customer for software application, if required.
- Software Development
 - Previous project:

- Laundry Management System (C#, Crystal Report, MS SQL Server, MS Access, Cloud and Radio-Frequency Identification (RFID))
- Dormitory Management System (VB.net, Crystal Report, MS Office Excel Reporting, MS SQL Server)
- Attendances Management System (JAVA, MS Access, MS Office Excel Reporting)

Reason of leaving:

- Looking for new challenge
- Looking for a more stable working environment
- Transport Problem, because company relocation

EDUCATION

2017 - 2019

- Bachelor of Science (Honours) Software Engineering from University of Portsmouth
- First Class Honours
- CGPA 4.07

2013

- Diploma in Information Technology in Olympia College Johor Bahru
- CGPA 3.45

2009

- Secondary Education (Sekolah Menengah Kebangsaan Taman Molek)
- Highest Qualification: Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia (SPM)

ACHIEVEMENTS & EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Certificate of achievement (LCCI Level 2 in Book-keeping and Accounts) (2009)
- Certificate of achievement (Highest Mark in Programming in C++)
 (2011)
- Certificate of achievement (Highest Mark in Visual Basic Programming)
 (2012)
- Certificate of achievement (Highest Mark in Java Programming)
 (2013)
- Certificate of achievement (Highest Mark in Data Communication and Networking)
 (2012)
- Certificate of achievement (Highest Mark in IT And Society)
 (2012)
- Agile Project Scrum Master (**PSM1**) (2016)
- University of Portsmouth Top Student Awards (2019)

SKILLS AND ABILITIES

Languages

• Proficiency in English - Speaking -7, Written- 5

• Proficiency in Malay - Speaking- 6, Written- 3

• Proficiency in Chinese - Speaking- 10, Written- 9

• Proficiency in Dialect

(Hokkien, Cantonese) - Speaking- 7

SKILLSET

Skillsets	No. Years Of Experience	Level
Programming Language		
ASP.Net	5	Advanced
C#	5	Advanced
SQL Statement	5	Advanced
JAVA	4	Advanced
Node.JS	2	Intermediate
VB.Net	3	Intermediate
VB6	2	Intermediate
Golang	1	Intermediate
PowerShell	1	Intermediate
Python	1	Beginner
C/C++	1	Beginner
Web Programming Language		
HTML	5	Advanced
CSS	5	Advanced
JavaScript	5	Advanced
TypeScript	3	Intermediate
JQuery	5	Advanced
XML	4	Advanced

Web Framework		
.Net Framework 4 & above	5	Advanced
Bootstrap	5	Advanced
Angular 7	3	Intermediate
ReactJS	1	Beginner
WCF Service	4	Advanced
SOAP Web Service	4	Advanced
RESTFul Web Service	4	Advanced
Application / Software		
Visual Studio	5	Advanced
Team Foundation Server (TFS Source	4	Advanced
Control System)		
NUnit & JUnit	4	Intermediate
DialogFlow (Google On Action)	3	Intermediate
Rational Team Concert (RTC)	2	Intermediate
Jenkins	2	Intermediate
Advanced Query Tools (AQT)	3	Advanced
Microsoft SQL Server Management 2008	4	Advanced
NetBean	2	Intermediate
IBM InfoSphere DataStage (ETL Tools)	3	Advanced
IBM Cognos Report	3	Advanced
Crystal Report	2	Intermediate
Microsoft Office Package	5	Advanced
Microsoft Visio	4	Advanced
Tricentis Tosca (RPA Tool)	2	Advanced
SoupUI	3	Intermediate
Appliance	'	·
IBM DataPower Gateway (SOA	2	Intermediate
Appliances)		
Radio Frequency Identification (RDIF)	3	Intermediate

OTHER RELEVANT SKILLS

- Have Full SDLC experience
- Agile Scrum Master (PSM1)
- Knows maintenance on computer's hardware and software.
- Have basic accounting knowledge (LCCI Level 2).
- Patient and eager to learn new technology such AI, Data Mining, Big Data and Data Analyst.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Availability : 1 month notice

REFERENCE

Reference 1

Name : Tok Woon Boon

Telephone No. : +65 94594585

Email : woonboon.tok@gmail.com

Position : Senior Manager

Company : Oversea-Chinese Banking Corporation Limited

Reference 2

Name : Joey Lai Poh Chi
Telephone No. : +65 96264784

Email : Joey_LAI_Poh_Chi@iras.gov.sg

Position : Account Manager

Company : Inland Revenue Authority of Singapore